BIO

Jonathan Berger is a designer, developer and technologist who has been active in the NYC technology community since 2005, helping to build events, products, and teams. He is an internationally sought speaker who talks about startups, technology, Lean, Agile, and design. As a consultant he's been on the team with almost 30 startups and enterprises in the past few years. As a startup founder he helped build one of the first online ecommerce fashion marketplaces. These days he's interested in building practice to make designers lives better.

SELECTED WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Director of Product Design, Pivotal Labs, NY, NY 2008-2015

Leading a team of ~10 designers, building an agile design practice and methodology.

Building web and mobile applications using Agile, XP, and Test-Driven methodologies.

Every day I code, design, anchor teams, lead inceptions, manage reports, and help run the office. At Pivotal I've also been a Designer, Engineering Manager, and Design Manager.

Co-founder, Market Publique, Brooklyn, NY 2008-2013

Helped design and build an online vintage fashion marketplace, helping people buy and sell vintage clothes and build community around fashion. Launched at SxSW in 2008.

Founder, Publique Domain, Brooklyn, NY 2008-2009

Spun a product design studio off of Market Publique, working with clients like Spot.Us, the Anti-Defamation League, and NewsTrust.

Designer, American Museum of Natural History, NY, NY 2007-2008

Developed animations and motion graphics for the the Interactive division of the Exhibitions department for the *Horses* and *Hall of Human Origins* shows.

Video Editor & Technology Consultant, MTV Networks, NY, NY 2006-2007

Edited and animated video, designed work protocols & archiving systems, and wrote documentation for TVLand.com.

SKILLS

Expert in Agile, Lean Startup, and Extreme Programming (XP) methodologies.

Experienced product designer (desktop and mobile), with a strong emphasis on User Experience (UX). Experienced with modern web development tools including Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS, and shell scripting. Adobe Certified Expert in Photoshop.

Extremely high level of proficiency in Vim, Adobe Creative Suite, AfterEffects, Final Cut Studio. Years of experience with Microsoft Office, OpenOffice, Filemaker and various productivity applications.

Extensive photography and videography production and post-production experience for broadcast and internet.

EDUCATION

New School University, NY, NYMaster of Arts in Media Studies, 2007

Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, NY Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy, 2001

PUBLIC SPEAKING & REFERENCES

Portfolio of talks at http://www.jonathanpberger.com/talks, references available upon request.